## Daniel Groleau

Denver, Colorado • (603) 913-3026 • ddgroleau@gmail.com • www.linkedin.com/in/daniel-groleau

## **Professional Summary**

Accomplished leader with a passion for logistics systems, cost savings and data analysis. Leads diverse teams to meet critical and challenging deadlines. Army veteran and MBA candidate with over four years' experience leading people and developing intuitive systems.

#### **Skills**

- Asset Management
- Financial Loss Mitigation / Cost Reduction
- Strategic Planning
- Sourcing & Procurement
- Supply Chain Management

- Risk Mitigation
- SAP and Oracle ERP Experienced
- Microsoft Office Suite;
   Advanced Excel User
- Data Analysis via Business Intelligence Tools

## **Work History**

Supply Chain Buyer / Planner (Asset Specialist II), 05/2020 to Present

#### Arrow Electronics (Hiring Our Heroes Corporate Fellowship Program) - Centennial, CO

- Manages procurement and fulfillment of electronics equipment from vendor/supplier to end customer. Manages supplier relationships and product inventory in excess of \$30m.
- Developed intuitive process-improvement tools, reduced purchasing time-spent by 75%.
- Exceeded customer expectations with aggressive fulfillment strategy, building trust and prompting customer to place multiple \$400k+ project orders with Arrow

#### Strategic Sourcing Manager, 01/2020 to 05/2020

#### United States Army - Fort Carson, CO

- Developed and implemented logistics strategy for a 500+ personnel organization; specifically
  assigned to manage implementation of new equipment and end-of-lifecycle or repurposing of
  legacy equipment.
- Coordinated with military leaders, manufacturers, and DoD contractors to complete over 400 proposed sourcing plans for Army equipment.
- Analyzed the financial impact of outbound and inbound equipment shipping methods to determine most cost-effective sourcing solutions.
- Negotiated procurement timelines to most effectively synchronize normal operations and new equipment fielding; developed and implemented six-month sourcing strategy to ensure that critical milestones within the project.

## $\textbf{Logistics / Supply Chain Manager}, 11/2018 \ to \ 01/2020$

#### **United States Army** – Fort Carson, CO

• Deputy Director of an intelligence and surveillance organization of 120 personnel; managed company assets valued at \$41,000,000. Rated #1 of 5.

- Directed logistical planning of company operations; managed the identification, acquisition, delivery, installation, and upgrade of military parts and supplies through SAP ERP.
- Developed new procurement, cost reduction, and loss recovery strategy; recovered \$900,000+ in costs; analyzed historical loss data and implemented preventative control measures.
- Managed maintenance and services for a fleet of over 65 tactical vehicles and hundreds of weapon systems, optics, lasers, and communications devices; maintained a 95% operationalreadiness status of all equipment.

## Intelligence & Surveillance Project Manager, 11/2017 to 11/2018 United States Army – Fort Carson, CO

- Directed operational performance, training, resourcing, health and welfare of 25 personnel; maintained an inventory of over \$5,000,000 of property and equipment; rated #1 of 8.
- Deployed to Kosovo in 2018; conducted intelligence and surveillance operations in Northern Kosovo; coordinated and executed joint peace-stability operations with NATO partners to improve religious and cultural stability in the region.
- Project lead for planning, marketing, and execution of an International Ranger Competition; trained and tested 50 participants from eight nations (UK, Denmark, Sweden, Ukraine, Poland, Austria, Hungary, US). Managed a planning team of 20 personnel and overcame budget obstacles in a foreign currency; received praise in Pentagon media release.
- Selected above 10 peers to serve at the Joint Multinational Readiness Center in Hohenfels, Germany; advised, trained and mentored 50 soldiers in preparation for global operations in Kosovo.

## **Operations Manager**, 08/2017 to 11/2017 **United States Army** – Fort Carson, CO

- Managed and resourced training land requirements on Fort Carson; negotiated land schedules and implemented co-use agreements between military and civilian organizations.
- Developed, implemented and supervised planning and scheduling processes for military operations to meet training objectives for a 500+ personnel organization.
- Managed supply chain lifecycle of ammunition, from forecasting requirements to disposal.
- Facilitated the transportation of 100+ military vehicles from Fort Carson, CO, to Fort Polk, LA via rail.

#### Education

## Master of Business Administration Candidate, Ohio University, Spring 2022 Operations and Supply Chain Management

 Currently enrolled in a part-time MBA program with a concentration in Operations and Supply Chain Management, expected graduation Spring 2022.

# **Bachelor of Arts**, University of New Hampshire, Class of 2016 **Political Science and Justice Studies**

- Graduated Cum Laude; 3.66 GPA; Member of UNH Army ROTC.
- Awarded George C. Marshall Leadership Award, #1 of 75 cadets in the UNH ROTC Program of 2015/2016.
- Selected over 20 seniors to serve as the Cadet Student Director (2015/2016) to lead a 75-cadet ROTC program.